





Summary

Jump to Section

Result-oriented Professional with over 5 years of experience in System Administration, Networking, Configuration Management, Windows Server Administration, Whare administration, Installation, Change Management, AD, DNS, DHCP, IIS, WSUS, WDS, IBMTSRM, BMC Remedy, MSTSC, MSRA, ESXI 6.0 & 6.5, VMware.

Work Experience

Arcis E services Pvt Ltd as System Administrator

Sep 2018 to Jan 2021

Managing and administrating windows desktops, Windows Servers and VMWare EXSI servers.

Handling the data center servers and monitoring the alerts on daily basis with threshold value.

Handling the Dell Power Edge R430, R440 & R530 servers with VM ware EXSI OS.

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Managing ESXI servers through the Virtual Center Server.

Create a VM and assign Virtual CPU, memory and disk partitions as per the requirement.

Install various OS in VM.

Performing Snapshots, when the hardware or software change or upgrade happen in server.

Creating templates from VMs as well deploy the VMs from templates.

Monitoring the servers using PRTG Tool

Troubleshot issues like CPU utilization, RAM utilization and drive Space utilization.

Performing daily data backup using the Autover tool.

Worked on Service request, Incident request and Change management request.

Responsible for updating and maintaining the users, groups and OU in AD server.

Responsible for applying password policy and account lockout policy in OU using GPO.

DNS server configuration and maintenance.

Installation and maintenance of DHCP, IIS and FTP.

Planning and maintaining monthly OS backup(system state backup) using the windows server databackup service.

Unlock and reset the domain user accounts.

Installing Various Operation System's through the WDS server.

Handling WSUS Server to update the monthy basis patches in client machine.

Installing, maintaining & Updating Symantec antivirus

Address user tickets regarding hardware, software and networking.

Walk customers through installing applications and computer peripherals.

Configuring mail account in Microsoft outlook.

Configuring local and network printers

Maintaining asset inventory of both desktops and servers.

Arcis e services pvt ltd as System Administrator Sep 2018 to Till Date

Worked on service request, incident and change management tickets.

1

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld Manage and administrator of VM Ware EXSI servers and Windows Servers.

Monitoring the servers using IBMTivoli monitoring tool.

Create a Whand assign Virtual CPU, memory and disk partitions as per the requirement.

Install various OS in VM.

Perform VMware Health Check Report and share the reports to Management.

Check V-Center server console for alarms and alerts.

Create the data store using NFS,

Performing Snapshots, Cloning and template.
Responsible for updating and maintaining the users, groups and OU in AD.

Configuring Group policy.

DNS and DHCP server configuration for the on premises domain.

Unlock and reset the domain user accounts

Installing Various Operating System through SCCM server. Installing windows patching through WSUS server. Planning and maintaining monthly OS backup.

Installing, maintaining & Updating Symantec antivirus.

Softenger Pvt Ltd as Windows and VMware Administrator

Dec 2017 to Aug 2018

IBMTSRMTicketing tool used for tracking the IT related issues.

Worked on service request, incident and change management tickets.

Manage and administrator of VMWare EXSI servers and Windows Servers.

Monitoring the servers using IBM Tivoli monitoring tool.

Create a VM and assign Virtual CPU, memory and disk partitions as per the requirement.

Install various OS in VM.

Perform VMware Health Check Report and share the reports to Management.

Check V-Center server console for alarms and alerts.

Create the data store using NFS,

Performing Snapshots, Cloning and template.

Responsible for updating and maintaining the users, groups and OU in AD.

Configuring Group policy.

DNS and DHCP server configuration for the on premises domain.

Unlock and reset the domain user accounts

Installing Various Operating System through SCCM server.

Installing windows patching through IBM Big Fix server.

Planning and maintaining monthly OS backup.
Installing, maintaining & Updating Symantec antivirus.

CMS IT Services Pvt Ltd as Customer Support Engineer

Oct 2015 to Dec 2017

BMC Remedy Ticketing tool used for tracking the IT related issues.

Responding to client support requests.

Contacting clients to find out the nature of the problem.

Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners.

Add a system from workstation to domain.

Installation of device drivers & hardware components.

Test alternative pathways until you resolve an issue.

Maintaining Desktops/Laptops and troubleshooting real time problems.

Repairing and replacing harware equipment as necessary.

Installing and troubleshooting of citrix receiver remote access Configuring and troubleshooting mail account in Microsoft outlook.

Installing, maintaining & updating Mcafee antivirus.

Monitoring computer software vulnerabilities.

Troubleshooting browser related issue in user profile.

Install windows 10 and 7 patches manually.

Configuring and troubleshooting of MS Outlook and skype for business.

Install and troubleshoot in SCCM client 2007/12.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Anna University in 2014

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Windows 7/8, Windows 10		
Windows Server 2008 R2,2012,2012R2 &2016		
AD, DNS, DHCP, IIS, File Server, WSUS		
IBM Tivoli Monitoring (ITM)		
PRTG Network Monitor		
ESX 6.0 & 6.5, VMware vCenter 6.0 & 6.5		
MSTSC, MSRA and Arcon RDP tool		
Symantec (SEP), MacAfee		
IBMTSRM, BMC Remedy		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
ENGLISH				
HINDI				
TAML				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: OBC - non-creamy
Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.